<<<<<<< Updated upstream
I only came here out of respect
=======
>>>>>>> Stashed changes
for my parents who...
(punch) (hit) (kick)
SPEAKER: Your father was more than just a "friend"
to my family.
♪ That was a long time ago1.
That was a long time ago2. ♪
Yes.
BANNER: Saved it for what?
- First speaker
on two lines.
ROB: Second speaker on one line.
- Continuation of first speaker
ROB: Continuation of second speaker.
- right here.
ROB: End of second speaker.
Let's just crawl into bed...
<<<<<<< Updated upstream
Sentence.
=======
SHOUT
>>>>>>> Stashed changes
...and eat.
It is imposible
to find out
what is good
and what is bad.
This is a Sentence
that is very long.
Institute of Mathematics
and Computer Science
of the University
of Latvia.
<<<<<<< Updated upstream
=======
This is a sentence...
..that I made...
ROB: here. Now it's gone.
Counterclockwise part.
This sentence is so long it exceeds the row limit of 37 characters and it might be reassembled in more than 3 lines.
>>>>>>> Stashed changes