We have to decide how we're
going to kill this bitch.
I know Fami's death
affected you deeply.
It hurt us all.
We can figure it out when
we get to the compound.
Let's kill her, record it and
see if that makes an impact.
Let's do it now!
Let's go!
Vámonos.
Go.
A little step. One more.
I got Amber!
Relax.
You made the right
decision not to kill her.
Let her rot in there.
It's worse than death.
We know where they
are taking her.
A cocaine place full
of Venezuelan army.
My friend,
let's not wait.
They killed my men.
They have to be
punished, and they will.
But the General is right.
We cannot engage on
this side of the border.
Attacking a facility on
this side of the border,
so closely tied to the
Venezuelan government,
would be seen as an act of war.
As Colombian Army, this is
as far as we can go for now.
It's time to go home and
face the politicians.
Let's go.
I'm staying.
By yourself? That's
not a good idea.
I can't go back without
her. You know that.
Good luck.
Thank you.
Rápido.
I had her, Dad.
In my arms. So close.
I could feel her
breathing on my back.
I can imagine.
She's brilliant.
She's the purest
soul I ever met.
She's a liar.
She is a liar.
That's a big lie,
working for the CIA.
It's not like, you know, lying
about some old boyfriend's big dick.
I don't know how you trust that.
Reminds me of the…
wisdom of one of my
mentors, Kenny Rogers.
You got to know when to hold 'em
Know when to fold 'em
Know when to walk away
Know when to run.
Come on.
Go on.
Yeah.
I'm in pain too, but
instead of thinking of that,
all you can do is revert
to your redneck loyalty.
You promised me when we got
married you wouldn't do this shit.
She's got a side thing she's
doing for the Agency down there.
Special status.
I've been all around the world.
You guys are both fucking liars.
They could hold her for 20 years
or they could kill her tomorrow.
You gotta know when to hold
'em Know when to fold 'em
Know when to walk away
Know when to run.
All right, talk to me.
So the book on that place
says it's like FedEx for the Venezuelan
drug cartel run by the military.
It's called Cartel de los
Soles, the Cartel of Suns,
which, if you
didn't already know,
is run all the way to the top
of the Venezuelan government.
Security is strong.
That's army on the outside if
you haven't already noticed.
Also, I feel the need to point out
that that's where they pay out ELN,
so there's gonna be
guerrillas hanging around.
– Blah, blah, blah.
– Those guys are no joke.
I can knock it over
in a couple of months.
How? There's no support within
the administration on this.
The White House doesn't
even wanna hear about her.
They won't engage, no
matter what any of us do.
So, what about Ground Branch?
No appetite. It's gonna sound harsh, man,
but not every problem has a solution.
I'll tell you another
problem without a solution.
When you wake up one morning
with a Glock in your mouth.
You notice I said
"Glock," not "cock?"
And let me tell you,
it won't feel good when that bullet opens
up your fucking skull like a watermelon.
That would be very
traumatizing for my husband.
– Oh, yeah.
– Listen, I'm not giving up.
Seventh floor is aware and concerned,
but for the moment, you're on your own.
Shall we order in tonight?
Cleaned up enough
messes for one day.
Talk to me.
It's Amber.
They're forcing me to
bury her. Bambi too.
What? What do you
mean? Where is she?
In some Venezuelan
hellhole. A drug facility.
He's wandering around
like a lost dog.
Well, you can't do that.
Amber's our friend.
And Bambi, Jesus Christ,
Mitch, he saved your life.
I mean, you gotta
get him outta there.
Come on. It's not
some eternal debt.
Pretty sure he can take care
of himself. He's fucking Rambo.
She knew the risks. It's
what she signed up for.
You've known her for 15 years. Amber's
not just a friend. She's family.
I'm just as upset
about this as you are.
There's nothing I can do, David.
Is everybody in your
life just an asset?
Am I?
Look, I have a job, and my job is
to consider the biggest picture.
And in the big picture,
it's easier if she stays.
I'm sorry to say it, but it is.
Plus, the upside,
from a national
security perspective…
The longer she stays in that prison, the
clearer it becomes how awful Maduro is
when it comes to human rights!
And you're being a
careerist weasel!
Wow. Must be nice to be able
to take the moral high ground?
Make you feel all
warm and cozy inside.
You know, I'd love to be up there too,
but unfortunately, I took an oath.
Yeah. I know all about it.
No, no. You'll listen.
The oath I took for my job?
What was it? Let's see.
Hard to remember. Oh, yeah.
Defend this country against all
enemies, foreign and domestic.
Bear true faith and
allegiance to the same.
I take this obligation freely,
without any mental reservation, et
cetera, et cetera, so help me, God.
It doesn't say jack shit in
there about being a good person.
Now I don't want you to get the
wrong idea about me or nothing,
but…
I'm not a drunk.
It's okay. Jesus doesn't judge.
I've saved some people.
Lot of people owe their lives.
And they like me.
Are you DEA?
Do I look like I give
a shit about cocaine?
I was a soldier.
– A soldier?
– Long time ago.
What do you do now?
I'm in tourism.
People wanna see the
authentic Colombia.
For the sunsets.
Landscapes.
You know, people, they
look at this forest
and they go, "How
beautiful." "How beautiful?"
I just see trees and plants, all
fighting each other for the sunlight.
All of them just racing
to the top of the canopy.
And then the slow
growers, they just…
die in the shade.
"Let not your hearts be troubled.
Neither let them be afraid."
That's John. Right?
Anyway, it was somewhere, but…
You're a believer.
That's great.
Well, God or the Devil.
Depends which side
of the gun you're on.
You're gonna fucking learn!
I don't know.
I've killed too
many men in my life.
Stay fucking down!
I've told you about
wearing those shorts!
Shut up!
Stay the fuck down!
See what I'm saying?
I was eight. You know?
You know what?
I'm a pretty good shot.
Wanna know the
secret? Repeatability.
You gotta hold the weapon the
exact same way every time.
Fuck it, you're gonna learn now!
You're gonna fucking learn...
Yes.
You're a protector.
Your family must be
really happy to have you.
Let's sleep together.
I should make you a hamburger.
You know what?
I should've played baseball.
I had a 72-mile-an-hour
fastball when I was 14.
That's really good, by the way.
Finish outside.
Go. Go play baseball outside.
Finally.
How did I get here?
I found you in the street.
Well, thank you for rescuing me.
I didn't think I'd made such
a good first impression.
You hungry?
It's…
From my cousin, Javi.
He's a fisherman.
"Follow me and I will
make you fishers of men."
Where does he get so much fish?
Next to the bridge, where
the current slows down.
By the big bridge?
Yes, but you can't go there.
Fishermen are very
territorial, especially Javi.
Buenos días.
This is where I fish, my friend.
You want me to swim over to the
other side and fish from Venezuela?
That's not my problem, man.
Aren't rivers for everyone?
This is where the
currents converge.
A man must fish
where the fish are.
A man has to be careful.
This is my spot.
Well, how about you take
all the fish that I get,
and you just give
me ten dollars?
What's your name?
Javi.
Me llamo Bambi.
It's funny, right?
I'm gonna make you rich.
Rich? How?
– How?
– Yeah.
With money.
Good.
– See you tomorrow.
– Mañana.
Mañana, amigo.
Okay.
Do you know what?
– What? Tell me.
– Cumbia is the best music in the world.
Look at this.
– Salud.
– Good. Good job.
Let's have beer.
We got five million in the
campaign exploratory account.
That's ten times what
anybody else has.
We got some heavy hitters coming
in. Lot of White House experience.
You're gonna have
big guns behind you.
Right. Good.
What's the matter? Your
head still in Colombia?
I know you gotta
be torn up inside.
Let's not do that.
– What?
– Talk about emotion.
Okay, tough guy.
But you need to understand
she is not coming out. Ever.
We did the research.
I spoke to the White House.
It is very sad. I liked her a
lot, but she is not coming home.
Well, now it's time to move
to the grown-ups' table
and make some decisions about your life
before life makes the decisions for you.
I'll do my best
to make you happy.
Christ.
When did you get so cynical?
I don't know. Maybe at Harvard.
It's fine. I just
wanted to be clear.
No, maybe you're right.
Maybe everybody's just, you know,
operating out of self-interest.
Maybe family is just some…
sentimental construct to justify
some heartless animal kingdom crap.
Maybe real love doesn't exist at
all, but I want you to remember,
I taught you how to
wipe your own ass.
I had your shit on my fingers.
And if you think that wasn't out of
love, you need to grow the fuck up.
Cynicism is a refuge for
the young and the childless.
Too much?
No.
Senator, I hope we
didn't keep you waiting.
Outside of the development team,
you're gonna be the
first to know about this.
– If you don't like it, I'll be devastated.
– Well, it's not up to me.
Let's see where the warfighters
put it on their list of priorities.
Speaking of which, we
have one right here.
– He's not the Joint Chiefs…
– Senator.
…but he knows the
truth on the ground.
I wasn't expecting to see you.
We're all very sorry for your loss.
Thank you.
I had an epiphany this
morning about politics,
and I wanted you to be the
first to hear about it.
My father... dad, does not
know what I'm about to say.
I'm intrigued.
I've been exploring a run for
the Senate seat opening up.
Could we talk
about your support?
I would love to talk
to you about it.
That's how you make history,
kids. Got a future president here.
Senator, I know
your time is short.
Reese, wanna kick it off?
Senator, may we
introduce you to Ulysses?
You feel it in your bones.
When that call comes in,
it's the tone of voice,
and you know something
bad has happened.
When you hear, "Your
wife has been kidnapped."
And it has shattered your core,
and makes you mad at God, and
you say, "How can God be good?"
And then you segue.
People like vulnerability.
And you take the lessons
that life has given you.
Everybody has loss.
Some people's loss
is worse than yours.
I think about a woman who's lost her
child because of substandard medical care,
and I know that I
wanna fight her fight.
And along with that is the importance
of stronger national security.
Americans should be free to travel
safely all around the globe.
And when anyone threatens that,
they should fear our wrath.
Make it your own, of course,
but something like that.
Hey, Boss. You got a sec?
Got a confession to make.
You got five minutes.
So, our hero gets picked up by
jungle bros we know are ELN.
Okay, you can assume
I paid attention.
Right. They drop her off in this
facility run by the Venezuelan military.
That suggests to me they
consider her a keeper.
Chit for sanctions, propaganda.
Maybe they don't know yet.
So, what's your confession?
Well, Amber's been good to the Agency,
and I'm personally tight with her brother.
He's done a lot of
favors for us in Iraq.
On the one hand, we have loyalty
and our integrity as human beings.
On the other hand, the price of
loyalty, in this case, is very high.
So there's an upside to
cutting ties right now.
But I still don't see
how it's my problem.
Well, I'm trying one last idea.
We could help Bambi
knock the place over.
Don't put any of
this on my desk.
Hey.
It's not a good time.
You're scared. It's cool.
Can I be rough?
I don't know, can you?
Is it "yes," or is it "no?"
Yeah.
I changed my mind.
What the fuck are we
doing? This is bullshit.
It's not.
I was pretty clear
about my motivations.
You're going through a lot 'cause
you're injured and your wife's in hell,
and that, I'm here to be the
companion in the hard times.
Well, thank you,
but I don't need it.
And I don't want it.
What about me? What
about what I want?
– You're so handsome.
– Jesus.
– Do you always do that?
– What?
Just push away compliments?
When they spring from
ulterior motives, yeah.
Handsome but so sensitive.
Trust me, nobody
has ever said that.
Well, maybe the people in your life
don't really see you for who you are.
I'm an outside observer here,
but yeah, you're sensitive,
and you're just trying
really hard not to show it.
Come on. Empathy.
Psychological insight.
And now I'm literally
on my knees for you.
You have to admit, it's
a pretty strong offer.