I only came here out of respect
for my parents who...
(punch) (hit) (kick)
SPEAKER: Your father was more than just a "friend"
to my family.
♪ That was a long time ago1.
That was a long time ago2. ♪
Yes.
BANNER: Saved it for what?
– First speaker
on two lines.
ROB: Second speaker on one line.
– Continuation of first speaker.
ROB: Continuation of second speaker
– right here.
ROB: End of second speaker.
Let's just crawl into bed...
SHOUT
...and eat.
It is imposible
to find out
what is good
and what is bad.
This is a Sentence
that is very long.
Institute of Mathematics
and Computer Science
of the University
of Latvia.
This is a sentence...
..that I made...
ROB: here. Now it's gone.
Counterclockwise part.
This sentence is so long it exceeds the row limit of 37 characters and it might be reassembled in more than 3 lines.
– If Minna's in there...
– I can't even think about that.
– I'm saying he might suspect...
– No. No, it looked like an accident.
then he's the one with the problem.
– Ja Minna ir tur iekšā...
– Nespēju par to domāt.
– Varbūt viņam radušās aizdomas...
– Nē, tas izskatījās kā nelaimes gadījums.
tad ķeza ir viņam.
All students will report
for their volunteer jobs
at 10:00 a.m sharp,
followed by a community lunch at 1:00.
That Becka had something
to do with Minna's death,
– or that we're trying to kill him?
– I don't know.
And now I don't know if I should talk
about the sad thing first
and then the happy thing?
Or do it the other way,
or maybe you don't wanna talk
about it at all.
– I can't talk, Matt.
– I have proof
– that the sisters were lying.
– What?
– He's not the Joint Chiefs…
– Senator.
…but he knows the
truth on the ground.